climaterealityproject.org 2019-06-12

# Privacy Policy | Climate Reality

###  PRIVACY POLICY  

_US Resident? See our[US Privacy Policy](https://www.climaterealityproject.org/us-privacy-policy)._

**1 Who we are**

We are The Alliance for Climate Protection d/b/a The Climate Reality Project, a U.S.-based 501(c)(3) non-profit (“Climate Reality” “we” “us” “our”) and we respect your privacy. This policy describes how we use your personal information if you are not a United States resident. 

When you, a resident 16 years of age or more of any country except the United States, visit and interact with Climate Reality you trust us with your information. There are many ways this information can help us make our service better. We can make sure you only see opportunities to take climate activism, communications about climate news, or to be involved in donation drives in which you're likely to be interested. We can remember your details so it's easier for you to connect with us. But we respect your privacy and we value the trust you've placed in us by sharing your information. This privacy policy sets out the way we use your information: what we collect, how we collect it, how we use it, why we use it, who we share it with and the rights to which you may be entitled. 

We have tried to keep this document as clear and direct as possible. If you have any questions or anything in this policy is unclear, please get in touch at the following email address: [GDPRprivacy@climatereality.com](mailto:gdprprivacy@climatereality.com). However there are contact details at the end of this policy if you have any questions or if anything is unclear. 

This privacy policy also covers our affiliated organizations that host our Climate Reality Leadership Corps program in different countries. Each organization is a joint data controller which may only use your data for the same purposes as Climate Reality and is listed here: 

  * Greenpeace in Central and Eastern Europe, a non-profit Society (Verein) with objectives that are of benefit to the public as laid down in §§ 34 to 47 of the Austrian Federal Fiscal Code located at Fernkorngasse 10, 1100 Vienna, Austria; 
  * Iniciativa Climática de México, A.C., a registered non-profit civil association in México located at Miguel Laurent 70-4 Col. Tlacoquemecatl del Valle, 03200 Cuidad de Mexico, Mexico; 
  * The University of Melbourne ABN 84 002 705 224, a university established in 1853 and constituted under the University of Melbourne Act of 2009 acting through its Melbourne Sustainable Society Institute, located at 1-100 Grattan Street, Parkville Victoria 3010, Australia; 
  * Green Box Trust d/b/a Food & Trees for Africa NPC, a nonprofit company incorporated under the Companies Act 71 of 2008 of South Africa located at 94 Bessemer Street, Wendywood, 2144 South Africa; 
  * Centro Brasil No Clima, an association in defense of social rights recognized as such by the Brazilian Ministry of Finance and located at Av. Marechal Camara, 160, sala 418, Rio de Janeiro 20 020-080, Brazil; 
  * Le Projet De La Réalité Climatique Canada, a charitable organization registered with the Canada Revenue Agency and organized under the laws of Quebec, located at 540-50 Sainte Catherine West, Montreal, Quebec, H2X 3V4, Canada; 
  * Perkumpulan The Climate Project Indonesia, a nonprofit association organized under the laws of Indonesia and located at Office 8 Building Level 18 A, Sudirman Central Business District, Jalan Jenderal Sudirman 52-53, Jakarta 12190, Indonesia, 
  * The Climate Project Foundation, an independent trust located at Paharpur Business Centre, 21, Nehru Place Greens, New Delhi, India 110019; 
  * World Wildlife Fund for Nature, a non-profit, non-governmental organization registered under Swiss law and registered by the Ministry of Civil Affairs of the People’s Republic of China, and located at Wenhua Gong, Room 1609, Beijing Working People's Culture Palace (Laodong Renmin Wenhuagong Dongmen), Beijing, Beijing 100006; and 
  * Bayay Sibuyanon, a registered non-stock and non-profit corporation located at Pag-alad Street, Poblacion, San Fernando, Romblon, Philippines. 

**2 Your information** _Data Collection and Usage_

We will collect and use your personal information to enable you to: 

1) subscribe to Climate Reality’s direct marketing communications (Subscriber); 

2) apply to, or support your membership in, a Climate Reality program (Member) including: 

the Climate Reality Leadership Corps and Membership access to RealityHub.climaterealityproject.org,  
Climate Speakers Network,  
a local Climate Reality Chapter,  
Climate Reality Campus Corps, or  
100% Committed (each a Climate Reality Program); and 

3) the purposes set out in more detail in this section. 

If you are a Climate Reality Program Member, you stay a Member until your membership is revoked or you withdraw your membership. To support your membership and comply with the agreement between yourself and Climate Reality, Climate Reality retains your data during your membership.

Your information may be shared with the data Controllers listed above and some third parties, as described below.

**What we collect**

**How we use it**

**Why we use it (Legal basis)**

**How long we keep it**

Information that we collect through your use of our website including: 

  * Device information such as operating system, unique device identifiers, the mobile network system; 
  * Hardware and browser settings; 
  * Date and time of requests; 
  * The requests you make; 
  * The pages you visit; 
  * Search engine terms you used to reach our website; 
  * IP address. 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Provide access to the website; 
  * Develop new opportunities to interact via the website; 
  * Improve our website and offers; 
  * Identify issues with the website and users’ experience of it; 
  * Monitor the way our website is used; 
  * Maintain website security. 

We use this information because: 

  * We have a legitimate business interest in understanding how our website is accessed, how it is used and any problems users have with it across multiple devices. 
  * We have a legitimate interest and a public interest in keeping our website free from malware, spyware, trojan horses, unauthorized entry, and third-party attacks like distributed denial of service attacks. 

We will keep this information for: 

  * A reasonable length of time not exceeding 3 years that lets us understand how people use our website and any technical issues they have. 

Information when you communicate with us whether in person, through our website or via email, over the phone, through social media or via any other medium, including: 

  * Your contact details (this may include your social media account if that's the way you communicate with us); 
  * The details of your communications with us; 
  * The details of our messages to you. 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Answer any issues or concerns; 
  * Monitor Subscriber and Member communications for quality and training purposes; 
  * Develop new services; 
  * Improve our services including by refining our direct marketing efforts and other operations to lower our costs; 
  * Making enquiries or informing you about your interactions with us (e.g. resolving issues with Direct Debits, or informing you of changes to events) 
  * Personalize our service; 
  * Providing you with information, services, or products that you have requested from us; 
  * Processing donations and fees received from you; 
  * Resolving and responding to your inquiries; 
  * Offering you ways to fund our work or volunteer your efforts, including surveys, online market research; 
  * Inviting you to become a Subscriber or Member; 
  * Reviewing our records, such as for financial audits; 
  * To prevent fraud, money-laundering, or terrorism efforts. 

We use this information because: 

  * We have a legitimate business interest in understanding Subscriber and Member feedback and in responding to Subscriber and Member communications in a consistent way. 

We will keep this information for: 

  * If you are a Member of a Climate Reality program, the duration of your Membership; 
  * If you are a Subscriber, the duration of your subscribership – You may unsubscribe at any time; 
  * If you are neither, the length of any contract between us or a reasonable amount of time not to exceed three years to understand how people interact with us and any technical issues that may require improvement. 

Information that you give us to subscribe to our Direct Marketing communications, whether online or in person including: 

  * Your contact details including: your name, address, email address; 
  * If you donate, payment details; 
  * Your expressed interests and preferences; 
  * Your preferences based on your interactions with us including which electronic communications you’ve clicked on or opened; 
  * Any other details you provide to us; 
  * The Climate Reality campaign, project, or event that you subscribe under. 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Provide our products and services; 
  * Manage and administer our services; 
  * Process your subscription; 
  * Onboard you as a Subscriber; 
  * Help us ensure that our Subscribers are genuine and to prevent fraud; 
  * Send personalised offers or climate advocacy ideas; 
  * Provide you or others with information, responses, or materials you or others have requested from us; 
  * Process donations and fees; 
  * Invite you to volunteer with us, or participate in surveys or research; 
  * Improve our direct marketing efforts for effectiveness and cost. 

We use this information because: 

  * We have a legitimate business interest in understanding customer feedback and in responding to customer communications in a consistent way. 

We will keep this information for: • 

Information about the way you use our services including: 

  * The things that you've subscribed under or downloaded from us; 
  * When and where you have subscribed to us and downloaded our materials; 
  * The timing and amount of any donations; 
  * Whether you’ve opened electronic communications from us; 
  * Whether you’ve left comments on any of our websites or engaged with us on social media; 
  * Whether you’ve clicked on links in electronic communications from us. 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Develop new services; 
  * Improve our services; 
  * Identify products and marketing that may be of interest to you; 
  * Personalise our service of things you’re interested in and how you use our services; 
  * Statistical analysis and research. 

We use this information because: 

  * We have a legitimate business interest to improve our service and better understand how Subscriber and Members use it. 

We will keep this information for: 

  * A reasonable length of time, not to exceed three years, that lets us understand how people use our services and the impact of any changes we make. 

Climate Reality program Members: 

Information you provide on your program application form, and subsequent reporting on Reality Hub, including your: 

  * Name and other identity data; 
  * Email address; 
  * Phone number; 
  * Gender; 
  * Training date(s) and location(s); 
  * Your biography, including age; 
  * Residence data; 
  * Citizenship data; 
  * Generalized, self-reported, non-tracked location data; 
  * Self-reported Acts of Leadership; 
  * Social media accounts; 
  * Languages; 
  * Employment data; 
  * Group or association data; 
  * Education data; 
  * Area(s) of speciality data; 
  * Interests of subject data. 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Offer you opportunities to take climate action; 
  * Offer you materials, resources, and information to support your membership; 
  * Provide our services; 
  * Set up your Reality Hub account; 
  * Match you with relevant action opportunities. 

We use this information because: 

  * For Members who are Climate Reality Leadership Corps Members, to support our contractual obligations to you. 
  * We have a legitimate business interest in enabling you to update your preferences and settings online. 
  * We have your consent as a Member to provide you information, resources, and opportunities related to the climate crisis, and to tailor that information to you. 

We will keep this information for: 

  * As long as you are a Member of the Climate Reality Program or you withdraw. 

Information that we collect from third-party partners which could include: 

  * Contact and donor information from charitable giving database providers; 
  * Contact and donor information from event organizers or commercial partners if you have specifically consented to have your data shared with Climate Reality in this way; 
  * Payment processing companies;Data brokers; 
  * Publicly available sources with data about your parliamentary constituency, characteristics of your local area, organizational directorships, estimations of your wealth or potential interest in legacy giving; 
  * Royal Mail’s National Change of Address and the BT Operator Services Information System (OSIS) file; 
  * Depending on your social media account settings, you may give us permission to access your information from those accounts. For example, if you sign up with a social media account, the social network may share your contact information with us; 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Provide our services; 
  * Manage and administer our systems; 
  * Take payment from or give you a refund; 
  * Help us ensure that our Subscribers and Members are genuine and to prevent fraud; 
  * Personalise our service; 
  * Statistical analysis and research into our clients; 
  * Combine this information with other types of information mentioned above. 

We use this information because: 

  * It is necessary for the contract to provide our services, that we collect information from some third party sources to process payments or give refunds; 
  * It is necessary to verify details to meet legal and regulatory requirements for identifying our Subscribers and Members; 
  * It is necessary in the public interest that we can verify identities and prevent fraud; 
  * We have a legitimate business interest in receiving information from other entities in our group/[other Members of our loyalty scheme] about shared Subscribers and Members; 
  * We have a legitimate business interest in understanding our Subscriber and Member base. 

We will keep this for: 

  * Information relating to payments or anti-fraud measures, the length of the contract between us and six years after, in case there are any issues. 
  * Information relating to statistical analysis, a reasonable length of time to help us better understand our Subscriber and Member base over time. [This will not be longer than two years but may be routinely refreshed.] 

Information that we collect incidentally from other sources or public sources, including: 

  * Information available in the media; 
  * Information presented on our social media timelines; 
  * Information collected by internet search engines; 
  * Public information collected by the U.S. Treasury Department and other government entities. 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Find other organizations with which to cooperate; 
  * Discover and evaluate possible sources for fundraising;Check donors’ information against third party sources; 
  * Facilitate our anti-terrorism, anti-money laundering efforts and ensure compliance with any international sanctions. 

We use this information because: 

  * We have a legitimate business interest in maintaining a public profile and being in both traditional and social media; 
  * We have a legitimate business interest in providing security over our business; 
  * We have a legitimate business interest in locating suitable sources for fundraising. 
  * We have a legal obligation to comply with sanctions and prevent support for money laundering or terrorism. 

We will keep this for: 

  * Information relating to media awareness and social media, for as long as the information is publicly available; 
  * Information collected incidentally by security systems we will keep this for as long as reasonable; 
  * Information relating to Fundraising, for as long as the information is publicly available; 
  * Information relating to our legal obligations, for as long as reasonably required to provide a record of compliance with the law. 

Information that we collect from individuals representing organisations, including: 

  * Contact details of individuals working for organisations; 
  * Details related to our interaction with those individuals; 
  * Other business-related personal information regarding such individuals. 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Build relationships with other organisations. 

We use this information because: 

  * We have a legitimate business interest in developing and maintaining relationships with vendors, partners and other companies and dealing with individuals who work for them in communicating about or solving the climate crisis. 

We will keep this for: 

  * The duration of our relationship with the relevant organisation and we are not made aware that the individual no longer works for them. 

Members only: Information that we collect or store through your use of Reality Hub including: 

  * Your password; 
  * Your account settings; 
  * Your account preferences; 
  * Your mailing address; 
  * Device information such as operating system, unique device identifiers, the mobile network system; 
  * Date and time of requests; 
  * The requests you make; 
  * The pages you visit and search engine terms you use; 
  * IP address. 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Provide our services; 
  * Develop new services; 
  * Improve our services; 
  * Identify issues with the website and user's experience of it; 
  * Match you with local presentation opportunities; 
  * Monitor the way our website is used; 
  * Manage and administer our systems; 
  * Identify how you'd like to use your account. 

We use this information because: 

  * For Members who are Climate Reality Leadership Corps Members, to support our contractual obligations to you. 
  * We have a legitimate business interest in understanding how our website is accessed, how it is used and any problems users have with it across multiple devices; 
  * Security monitoring. 

We will keep this information for: 

  * As long as you are a Member of the Climate Reality Program or you withdraw. 

Information that you give us to make a purchase, whether online or over the phone including: 

  * Your contact details including: your name, address, email address; 
  * Your payment details; 
  * Information about the items purchased. 
  * The product purchased 

We use this information, including to: 

  * Provide our products and services; 
  * Manage and administer our services; 
  * Process your order; 
  * Take payment from or give you a refund; 
  * Onboard you as a Subscriber or Member; 
  * Help us ensure that our Subscribers and Members are genuine and to prevent fraud. 

We use this information because: 

  * It's necessary to perform the contract. 

We will keep this information for: 

  * The length of the contract between us and up to six years after in case there are any issues. 

**Automated decision making**

We do not make solely automated decisions based on your data. 

If you have any questions about this, you can contact us at following email address: [GDPRprivacy@climatereality.com](mailto:gdprprivacy@climatereality.com). Legal requirements 

We need to collect certain types of information about your identity for compliance with legal requirements relating to our anti-terrorism and anti-money laundering obligations. If this information is not provided we cannot agree to provide a product or service for you. 

Your personal information may also be processed if it is necessary on reasonable request by a law enforcement or regulatory authority, body or agency or in the defence of a legal claims. We will not delete personal information if relevant to an investigation or a dispute. It will continue to be stored until those issues are fully resolved. 

**Special information we collect**

Certain types of personal information are more sensitive than others. "Special information" about you includes information about health, disability, race, ethnicity, union Membership, criminal offences (or alleged offences), political opinions, biometrics, and religion. 

We may collect and receive special information about you. We have identified here the types of special information we may collect or receive, how we will use it and why we will use it. 

Climate Reality Leadership Corps applicants are enrolled as Members once they complete the training. If you are a Climate Reality Leadership Corp Member, you stay a Member until your Membership is revoked or you withdraw your Membership. To support your Membership and comply with the agreement between yourself and Climate Reality, Climate Reality retains your data during your Membership. 

_Please do not tell us whether you are a member of a trade union, any information that could imply your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, criminal history, sexual life or orientation. Similarly, please only inform us of your health issues or other dietary requirements that could imply religious or philosophical beliefs to ensure that your needs are accommodated at a physical Climate Reality hosted event. Occasionally, and for anonymous and statistical data, we may inquire after your racial or ethnic origins, as noted below._

What we collect – Climate Reality Leadership Corps Members and Climate Speakers Network event attendees only 

How we use it 

Why we use it 

How long we keep it 

Information that you voluntarily self-report to us: 

  * Specifying certain dietary requirements that may imply specific religious beliefs or medical conditions; 
  * Disclosing certain titles and honorifics that imply specific religious beliefs; 
  * Disclosing to us certain health-related accommodation issues for access at events we host; and 
  * Ethnic or racial identity. 

We use this entirely voluntary information to: 

  * Provide you accommodations at our events related to your dietary needs or your health-related; 
  * Provide you access to spiritually-related (but not any one religion or denomination) climate activism events and opportunities; 
  * Provide you with the honorific(s) you prefer in communications; 
  * To provide anonymized and statistical data about attendance at our events to donors, potential donors, and others. 

We use this information because: 

  * Because you have voluntarily self-reported and consented that we may process this information for those reasons; 
  * Because you may have negative health effects if we do not process this information; 
  * Because processing the information is necessary in the public interest to comply with health-related accessibility laws; 
  * Because processing may be necessary and in the public interest for donors and the public who may have an interest in whether we provide an equitable program to all segments of society. 

We will keep this for: 

  * Your health-related accessibility issues and any dietary restrictions that may or may not imply health conditions or religious beliefs are only retained prior to and during your attendance at an event we host. 
  * The Ethnic or racial identity and your religious honorific are retained for the duration of your Membership. 

Information we share 

There are certain circumstances where we may transfer your personal data to employees, contractors and to other parties. 

  * We may share your information with certain contractors and service providers. They may process your personal data for us, for example, if we use a marketing agency. Other recipients/service providers include public relations agencies, IT specialists, database providers, production assistance, screening specialists, logistics contractors, backup and disaster recovery specialists, and email marketing providers. 
  * Our suppliers and service providers will be required to meet our standards on processing information and security. The information we provide them, including your information, will only be provided in connection with the performance of their function. 
  * We may also share your information with certain third parties. We will do this either when we receive your consent or because we need them to see your information so that we can provide products or services to you. These include anti-fraud and anti-terrorism databases, screening agencies, and other partners we do business with. 

Your personal information may be transferred to other third-party organizations in certain scenarios: 

  * In the unlikely scenario where we may transfer a Climate Reality program to be administered by another non-profit organization the information may be transferred to the next non-profit organization under suitable terms as to confidentiality; 
  * If we are reorganised into a slightly-different non-profit organization, information may be transferred to the succeeding non-profit organization who can continue to provide services to you; 
  * If we're required to by law, or under any regulatory code or practice we follow, or if we are asked by any public or regulatory authority – for example requests by law enforcement; 
  * If we are compelled to disclose the names and contact information of people who have signed petitions, we may provide the information to verify the accuracy of the petition and to prevent multiple submissions by the same person. 
  * If we are defending a legal claim your information may be transferred as required in connection with defending such claim. 

Your personal data may be shared if it is made anonymous and aggregated, as in such circumstances the information will cease to be personal data. 

**Where your information will be held**

You explicitly consent that when we share your information, your information may be transferred to a country outside the European Economic Area without an adequacy decision or appropriate safeguards pursuant to Article 46 of the GDPR. The risks are that your data could be hacked or misused by those who inappropriately gain access. 

We store our information on cloud servers located in the United States, where our offices are and where we on-board our Members and Subscribers, which does not have equivalent data protection laws to those applicable in Europe and is not subject to an adequacy decision under the GDPR. The transfer of this information is governed by data protection addenda including standard contractual clauses (SCCs) approved by the European Commission. 

We will only transfer data to jurisdictions outside the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) where the appropriate safeguards set out in the GDPR are in place. 

We are happy to provide you with slightly-redacted copies of the data privacy addenda with regulator-approved SCCs, which you can request from us via our contact information, below. 

**3 Your rights**

You may have certain rights in relation to your information including a right to access or to correct the information we hold on you. Other rights may be available in certain circumstances. Please click here to see more detail about the rights that may available and how you can get in touch with us. 

_Data Subject Rights_

We've listed the rights you have over your information and how you can use them below. These rights are subject to restrictions in the European General Data Protection Regulations and, subject to the exemptions in that law, may only apply to certain types of information or processing. 

Climate Reality Leaders with accounts on Reality Hub should also change your Reality Hub preferences or settings under "My Account". Reality Hub is a separate 

We need your consent for some of the ways we use your information, for example for marketing.  
You can remove that consent at any time. 

You can ask us to confirm if we are processing your information. 

You can ask to access your information in an easily readable format. 

You can ask to correct or update your information if it's wrong or has changed. 

You have a right to be forgotten and you can ask us to delete our copy of your information. 

You can email your request to us at [GDPRprivacy@climatereality.com](mailto:gdprprivacy@climatereality.com) or by using [this form](https://www.climaterealityproject.org/content/form-request-climate-reality-delete-my-data). 

It may not always be possible for you to use this right if, for example, if it is still necessary for us to perform the contract or we need to keep the information by law or because of a legal dispute. 

You can ask us to restrict how we use your information. 

You can ask us to help you move certain of your information to other companies. 

To help with that you have a right to ask that we provide your information in an easily readable format to another company. 

You can email your request to us: [GDPRprivacy@climatereality.com](mailto:gdprprivacy@climatereality.com) or by using [this form](https://www.climaterealityproject.org/content/access-my-personal-identifiable-information-held-climate-reality). 

You can ask us to stop using your personal information, but only in certain cases. 

**How to contact us**

If you have any questions about this policy please contact: [GDPRprivacy@climatereality.com](mailto:gdprprivacy@climatereality.com) or +1.202.567.6800 or555 11th Street NW, Suite 601  
Washington, DC 20004, USA. 

**Changes to the policy**

This policy will be changed from time to time. 

If we change anything important about this policy (the information we collect, how we use it or why) we will highlight those changes at the top of the policy and provide a prominent link to it for a reasonable length of time following the change. This is the first version of this policy. Once we update it, you can email us for previous versions at the following email address: [GDPRprivacy@climatereality.com](mailto:gdprprivacy@climatereality.com). 

**Other policies**

**Donor Privacy Policy**

Rules apply to donations to 501(c)(3) non-profit organizations like Climate Reality, and we strive to have a transparent and accountable [Donor Privacy Policy.](https://www.climaterealityproject.org/us-privacy-policy#donorpolicy)

###  Cookies  

We use cookies that identify your browser or device. They collect and store information when you visit our website [or app] about how you use it. 

For more information about cookies, the types of cookies we use and how we use them please see our: [Cookie Policy](https://www.climaterealityproject.org/us-privacy-policy#cookiepolicy). 

Security 

We are committed to keeping your personal information safe. We've got physical, technical and administrative measures in place to prevent unauthorised access or use of your information.
